Guide to the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 Records WAG.118
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 Records
1880-2019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 1 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 66
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 41 (Woodside, Queens, N.Y.)
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 21
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 34
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 30
Lanzafame, Santo
WAG.118
51.5 Linear Feet in 40 record cartons, 17 manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes, 2 custom boxes, and 1 card box
29 audiocassettes
1 websites in 1 archives website
The International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 was granted a charter by the National Union of Bricklayers of the U.S.A. on October 17, 1868 in Brooklyn, New York and is one of the oldest continuously-existing locals in New York City. The National Union of Bricklayers was one of the first unions to support the eight-hour work day. The collection consists of materials from Local 1, as well as Locals 9, 21, 34, 41, and 66 which merged with Local 1. Materials include early ledgers, correspondence, ephemera, photographs, scrapbooks, audio recordings, and an archived version of Local 1's website. Physical materials date from the 1880s to the 1990s, and the archived website captures are ongoing since 2012.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records of International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 of Brooklyn, New York and other locals it merged with, including Local 9 of Brooklyn, Local 41 of Woodside, Queens, and locals 21, 30, 31, 34, 37, 66 and 84. Materials and documents date from the 1880s to the 1990s and include ledger books, minutes, contracts, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, ephemera and audio recordings of meetings and conventions. Early ledgers of Locals 1 and 9 date from the 1880s to the 1930s and include minutes, dues records, expense and benefits books and apprentice lists. The collection also contains the archived website of Local 1, with captures ongoing since 2012. Photographs include portraits of individual members, union events, and group portraits of union members from the 1920s to the 1980s. A 1940s-era scrapbook from Local 41 includes head shots and group portraits of union members and related clippings. A photograph album that appears to date from the 1920s-1930s includes approximately 105 small black and white head shots of union members with names written in pencil under each.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1, in 1998. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1998.020 and 1998.021.
The website was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2012 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragility of materials in Boxes 1 and 2, researchers must use the microfilm of the early minutes of Local 9 (microfilm collection number R7459). Also because of fragility, advance notice is required before using a 1920s-1930s-era photographs album in Box 48.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials and archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Historical Note
The National Union of Bricklayers of the U.S.A. was organized on October 16, 1865 and granted a charter to Local No. 1 in Brooklyn, New York, on October 17, 1868, making Local 1 one of the oldest continuously-existing locals in New York City. The National Union of Bricklayers was one of the first unions to support the eight-hour work day, a priority for delegates from its New York locals to its 1869 Convention. In 1881, the National Union of Bricklayers became an international union. A reorganized charter was granted in 1910 when the International became Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers International Union of America. In 1916, the union became affiliated with the American Federation of Labor. From its beginnings the union emphasized apprenticeship training, wages, working conditions, and benefits for union members and their families.
The union's records illustrate the early dominance of Irish American and Irish immigrant members in the union -- many of them sons of bricklayers. In the 1930s and 1940s members from Irish and Italian ethnic backgrounds clashed, as Irish membership dwindled, and Italian members brought in more family members. By the mid-1980s, union operations were run at the district and international level, rather than at the local level, and local politics and power became less important. In 1986, Local 1 had 447 members, half of whom were African American and Latino, and the remainder were mostly of Italian origin. During the 1980s and 1990s, the International operated a federally-funded program called the Job Corps for Disadvantaged Youth, which trained female as well as male apprentices for Local 1.
Since its founding, Local 1 merged with several other locals, including locals 9, 21, 30, 31, 34, 37, 41, 66 and 84. Local 1's members have worked on New York City landmarks such as Grand Central Station, the Chrysler Building, the Metropolitan Life Building, the American Museum of Natural History, Lincoln Center, the Cloisters, the Frick Museum, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and thousands of office and residential buildings.
Sources:
Bates, Harry. Bricklayers' Century of Craftsmanship: A History of the Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers' International Union of America. Washington, D.C.: Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers' International Union of America Washington, D.C., 1955.
Hommel, Claudia. New York City Labor Records Survey, Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, 1986.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Accruals
New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Ledgers (account books); Building trades -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States.; Bricklayers -- Labor unions; Labor unions -- New York (State); Photographs.; International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 1 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Lanzafame, Santo
- Local 9: Ledgers and Minutes, 1880-1985 (Box 1, Box 2, Box 4, Box 8, Box 9, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 39, Box 42, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 43, Box 47, Box 61)
- Local 9: Candidates Books, 1923-1931 (Box 3, Box 43)
- Local 9: Membership Address Books, 1923-1990 (Box 3, Box 4, Box 43)
- Local 41: Correspondence, 1962-1992 (Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 63)
- Local 41: Contracts and Constitutions, 1952-1987 (Box 6)
- Local 1: Photographs, undated (Box 7)
- Frank Alessi: Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7)
- Photograph Plates, undated (Box 7)
- Local 21: Correspondence and Monthly Dues Reports, 1980-1992 (Box 10)
- Local 66: Apprentice, Journeyman, Transfer, and Reinstatement Forms, 1978-1984 (Box 10)
- Local 34: Correspondence, 1957-1993 (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 39)
- Local 1: Deceased and Dropped Members Forms and Ledgers, 1915-1993 (Box 13, Box 14, Box 38, Box 53, Box 54, Box 59, Box 41)
- Group Photographs, 1946-1952 (Box 16)
- Locals 30 and 41: Legal Decisions, 1978 (Box 16)
- Local 66: Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 34)
- Local 66: Audio Recordings of Board Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
- Local 66: Contracts, 1975-1990 (Box 21, Box 34)
- Trade Agreements and Constitutions, 1926-1970 (Box 21)
- Notices, 1927-1929 (Box 21)
- Dropped and Deceased Members Book, 1949-1992 (Box 23)
- Dues Books, 1921-1995 (Box 23, Box 38)
- Local 1: Photographs of Life Members, 1947 (Box 23)
- Local 30: Correspondence, 1981-1993 (Box 23, Box 24, Box 25)
- New York District Council Reports and Conference Materials, 1988-1990 (Box 25)
- Local 34: Minutes, 1899-1971 (Box 26, Box 27, Box 56, Box 57, Box 28, Box 39)
- District Council Reports, 1984-1987 (Box 26, Box 63)
- Audio Recordings of Executive Committee, General, and Special Meetings, 1988-1991 (Box 30)
- Local 1: Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 30)
- Local 9: Constitutions, Trade Agreements, and Dues Information, 1910-1992 (Box 32, Box 33)
- Local 9: Financial and Legal Documents, 1973-1993 (Box 32)
- Local 9: Election Ballots, 1936-1989 (Box 32)
- Local 9: Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1981-1991 (Box 32)
- Local 9: Correspondence, 1982-1993 (Box 32)
- Local 66: Picket Line Rosters, 1992 (Box 33)
- Local 21: Meeting Minutes, 1958-1992 (Box 34)
- Local 21: Correspondence, Stationery, and Financial Documents, 1971-1988 (Box 34)
- Local 21: Member Address Book, undated (Box 34)
- Local 1: Initiation Ledgers, 1916-1959 (Box 58)
- Local 1: Transfers In and Out Ledgers, 1916-1958 (Box 38, Box 58)
- Local 34: Notes, 1992 (Box 39)
- Local 34: Photographs, 1924 (Box 39)
- Local 34: Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
- Local 34: Member Lists, 1924-1937 (Box 39)
- Local 66: General Files, 1942-1993 (Box 30, Box 31, Box 40, Box 60)
- New York State Conference of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsman Annual Convention Proceedings and Audio Recordings, 1947-1987 (Box 40, Box 60)
- Local 66: Meeting Minutes, 1982-1993 (Box 30)
- Local 1: Financial Ledgers, 1959-1990 (Box 41)
- Local 1: Minute Books, 1959-1990 (Box 41)
- AFL-CIO Publications, 1977-1989 (Box 41, Box 45)
- Local 9: Dues Book, 1909-1910 (Box 43)
- Local 9: Items Removed from Minutes, 1885-1973 (Box 44)
- Local 1: Ledger; Local 9: Minutes, 1896, 1929-1930 (Box 46)
- Local 9: Ledgers and Membership Lists, 1906-1930, 1957-1979 (Box 47)
- Local 1: Apprenticeship Training Photographs, circa 1995-circa 1997 (Box 48)
- Local 1: Photographs of Restoration of Building at 71st and Park, circa 1990 (Box 48)
- Local 41: Scrapbook [Includes Clippings and Photographs of Members], circa 1940s (Box 48)
- Scrapbook [Includes 105 black and white photographs; names written in pencil under each], circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 48)
- Photographs of Union Officers and Events [Includes Group and Individual Portraits], circa 1930s-circa 1980s (Box 48)
- Head shots of Union Members, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 48)
- Memorial Poster for Thomas F. Murphy, circa 1989 (Box 48)
- Local 1: Photograph of 90th Anniversary, Nov 20, 1964 (Box 48)
- Local 34: Financial Ledgers, 1933-1952 (Box 55, Box 56, Box 57)
- Local 37: Minute Book and Financial Ledger, 1972-1982 (Box 59)
- Constitutions and By-laws, 1964-1985 (Box 40)
- Local 21: Embossing Press, Undated (Box 52)
- Local 3: Dues Books, 1888-1909 (Box 45)
- Local 1: Welfare Fund Reports, 1990 (Box 45, Box 63)
- Archived Website, Dec 5, 2012-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Scope and Contents
  The archived website of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 contains information for members, the local's newsletter, information about and photographs of events, calendars for events and trainings, and news listings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.